today's episode starts in an unlikely
place normally i start off every episode
at my base
but today i thought it would be a good
idea to show you exactly what i've been
doing and while i strictly speaking keep
all grinding off camera
look at this i have to
to show you
so i've got a shulker full of gravel a
shock full of gravel and quartz gravel
quartz now these are all blocks of
quartz and then these are all stacks
sand and gravel sand that took a really
long time to acquire and most of this
will be heading into stock in my
traveling shop
i'm getting rather fond of making money
now it's actually really useful but
especially with my rocket habits of just
using as many as possible and i've also
made so much progress on the base that
i'm starting to really run out of
resources again
here we are back in the shopping
district and there's the traveling cart
uh i'm gonna restock and see if we've
made any more cash i am chock full of
stuff right now
huh looks pretty good
except
except where's he gone
where's the old man is this a bug
it can't this isn't just a bug he's
has someone stolen old man green
the fish head green just his walking
stick
maybe i should put a missing person's
like thing up here cleo did such a good
job on putting these items up here
and
it's gone the old man is
he's totally gone
oh dear
anyway have we made any money
not from the sand can thankfully refill
all of that
and gravel
oh yeah gravel seems to be much more
popular how many is that
ten diamonds not bad i actually have a
fish head back at my base so i'm
definitely gonna make a missing person's
poster where the heck has he gone
and also i saw earlier today as i was
mulling about
i saw a little something over on that
hill now i don't know if he already
belongs to someone but i haven't seen
one in ages there he is the skelebone
horse the skeleton horse himself i don't
actually know i think like a lightning
bolt has to hit a horse maybe for this
to happen
but i i want it so i've asked someone
for a saddle and they thankfully gave it
to me jeven thank you very much my
saddle
and no one's claimed him he doesn't have
a saddle someone sat on him enough so
he's obviously been found before look he
doesn't kick me off when i sit on him
but if i put this on does this mean i
can yes
i does this mean he's mine no one seems
to have claimed him no one's given him a
name tag
can i keep him can i can i can i keep
him please
oh this is brilliant
even though i fly everywhere
there's nothing wrong with a pet horse
so now we just have to come up with a
name for him now i don't have a name tag
on me nor do i know how i'm gonna get
him across the water can i put him in a
boat maybe
i'm sure we can put him in a boat oh but
before we go the other thing was that i
wanted to do should have done this
perhaps first since sand isn't as
popular at all i think what we're gonna
do
is replace
this sand
with quartz or at least some of it with
quartz it's still the same price one
diamond equals two stacks that is 16
blocks right there so two one diamond
equals 32 blocks and that's cheaper than
next door i'm straight up undercutting
this guy
who is selling one diamond for 64 quarts
so i'm selling double that and that's
pretty good i think
and now we just need to figure out how
to get this little guy back to the base
i'm thinking we have to use a boat but i
don't even know if that works if not
we're going to have to make a very long
little trail to get him over to the base
but then
if he's at the base i can't really use
him
hmm
we'll have to think about this let's see
if we can push him into the boat i don't
i honestly have no idea if this works
i've never got a horse before
does it work
does he go in
does he he sings
that can't be right
oh he's just gonna drown isn't he
does he get affected by the conduit
power maybe
how do i get him in the boat
he sinks like a stone i'm basically not
gonna be using this horse
i'm gonna just i was gonna keep him as a
pet i was gonna call him jack
skellington or something and i'm gonna
keep him as a pet but i can't see a way
how to get him to my base
but he does sink like a stone and
doesn't kick me out so i'm wondering if
the conduit power
will keep this guy alive as well
if i'm fast enough maybe i shouldn't
have named him
all right let's go for it let's just see
if he doesn't drown
let's go
down we
go this is ridiculous
is he gonna make it
oh no the bubbles the bubbles taking it
down
conduit power
does it work on horses
do i have myself an underwater horse
oh this is
this is fantastic
i never thought of this at all
this is
this is the silliest submarine i think
i've ever seen it seems like the conduit
power affects him as well but i don't
know if he actually does drown anyway so
we could be in luck here
we could be totally in luck
tell you what if i put him
if i put him inside here i don't know
how skeleton horses works but this is
hilarious i assume he doesn't drown
because he doesn't have lungs he doesn't
kick me off in the water so this is an
aquatic horse he even jumps not well
kind of jumps
does he get affected by the bubbles do
we both go through
no no no no no
no no no
no
enough enough enough enough
jack skelebone
i
i was so close
oh no
oh
how distraught did i i even i got my
saddle back
oh
no
why did he
drown i thought he was getting stuck in
the blocks but i don't oh maybe i just
wasn't quick enough
i don't really know what to do with
myself now
oh we were gonna make the missing person
sign because my old man's gone missing
and
hold on
where's paul where on earth has paul
gone
someone must have taken him in my like
weeks of being friends with paul he
hasn't once
got out of the aquarium not once this is
devastating
i've lost everyone
i've lost the old man
i've lost puff fish paul
i've just lost my new friend jack
skelebone oh i feel so
bad everyone i love leaves me
[Laughter]
what is going on we have not had a good
start to this episode
anyway i think we should just continue
with building the base because i've made
well i've made a profit but i've also
made a really decent amount of progress
as well so last episode we actually
completed this first layer now people
are saying it looks like a coffee cup it
looks like a blender whatever i know it
doesn't really look like much yet but
that's because it hasn't reached its
full potential what i've also done in
the meantime is i've started working on
this outer layer down here is going to
be
a pretty cool
looking aquarium and all sorts of things
i've even used pickles around the edge
to try and light it up but down there is
going to be a really cool coral reef
this took a lot of resources all of
these resources were supposed to go up
there but they didn't not yet i need to
sort out this bottom bit to give it a
bit more leverage but i have indeed
started working on the top there's a
giant oh no
what's going on here
who's done this
whoever's done this look i started
making some glass stuff here
i hope they haven't removed my okay they
haven't done any damage to my glass work
but there's no way this is staying here
this has got to go
this is all got to go
oh how annoying this has all got to go
so did they build this by hand because
there's no way you can spawn a tree that
big
what is this for
your flower pot was looking a bit empty
oh right okay i get it so you think that
my base
looks like a flower pot
so a coffee cup i can understand but a
flower pot come on
doesn't look like a flower pot although
it is looking pretty cool i gotta admit
right what's this about then so i heard
that you cannot afford logs at the
moment oh no
not a problem this giant spruce tree is
a gift from you
from big logs inc i'll even help you
chop it down
details inside
red dog
so this is me getting my comeuppance
for the under my part in the undercut
scenario
i probably should give a little bit of
backstory
before
i go inside here
so i i now understand why this has taken
place
what an elaborate reaction okay so
let's go over to the shopping district
and find out what this is all about this
is rendog's shop logs inc
and a few episodes ago i needed some
logs but i didn't want to pay the price
that he was going so what i did was i
went to cub fans tree farm and tried to
steal
but i got caught in the act and in
return i built this
this acts in the middle of his shop it's
called undercut so in reaction to making
this
he's gone and made a giant tree he must
have spent a long time and now that he's
done that it really does look like a
flower pot but don't worry we were
working on it i promise
right let's go and have a look inside
and let's destroy some of this while
we're here as well
okay run
oh no i knew it i knew it
oh no
there it goes
oh
at least i don't have to clean that up
and i get a decent amount of wood out of
this
it's more of a gift more than anything
oh my goodness is that gonna decay
no it's not
that's not gonna decay at all
that was
because he's placed this by hand he
spent ages making a giant minecraft tree
that's not going anywhere
that's not going to decay at all
oh jeez
i think i have the solution to this
problem though
so what we're going to do we're going to
go up to
we're going to go up to this bit here
and we're going to set it on fire we
don't want this giant leaf monstrosity
here burn burn tree burn ow don't burn
yourself
burn burn the leaves all down
flower pot
i won't stand oh there's no fire spread
on this server is there's no fire spread
to protect everyone's buildings i do
have to destroy this manually oh my
goodness i've just made it a hell zone
now i've just made this even more
dangerous for me let's try again so
fire's not gonna cut it
we're gonna have to cut it by hand with
shears
how annoying is this it won't take too
long to clear because shears are very
very fast he could have at least put tnt
in the leaves
you know what next time i'm just gonna
buy the logs at least maybe when i need
leaves maybe one day i'll have a bunch
but man oh man
and we're done
look at all these leaves on the ground
that was a waste of iron in my time oh
of course i left a bit up there you've
got to commend rendog on his valiant
effort put in here he didn't really have
to terrain all of this with leaves with
grass and dirt and
even long grass he didn't need to do
this but he did he spent a lot of time
terraining the top of this to make it
look more like a flower pot so that he
could make this gigantic tree
unbelievable
let's see if i can do the flyby and get
this bit of leaf
my flying skills has improved
yes oh look at that skillfully done
fortunately i have a super shovel so
this isn't going to take any time at all
did i just hear death
yes i did yes i did where's my sword
when you need it oh i clearly haven't
slept in a while oh they're here they're
still flying about
oh i got him i'm pretty sure i got him i
did i got the xp
that was
x x-e-i-z
uma has just arrived and he's asking
what's going on rendog happened
ren dog happened that's that's what
happened i'm curious to see just how
crazy saying zuma's name is gonna get
right the cleanup operation continues
this shouldn't take too long and then we
can get back to building this thing do
you know what's funny is that one day
this area might actually be some kind of
nature reserve or some kind of biome
inside of the the glass shell but
there's no way i can i can build in here
with all of this stuff still here so
maybe one day all of this stuff will end
up back and it will look like a flower
pot but not today we did actually get a
decent amount of resources out of this i
just wasn't quite prepared
for how much cleanup there was going to
be
oh
wait there's a chest here
dearest grien i hope this prank wasn't
too taxing oh no it wasn't too axing on
you oh come on enjoy your pile of
charcoal rendog nice giant axe bro right
so i was correct
he was getting me back for the giant axe
but at least he complimented it
it seems like this is a season full of
puns
it's finally fixed look at this mess
look how many blocks i am lagging
because of this i need to clean this up
asap
and it's finally all collected this is
how many
bits of resources rendog put into this
excluding all the stuff that blew up
look at this and then there was loads of
stacks of leaves involved
like he must have spent a long time on
it so i can't even be mad i mean i'm a
prankster myself that was a pretty
dedicated prank he must have spent a
long time on it and it turns out that
rendog was actually stalking me with his
camera account he wanted to see me set
it off for his own video right so that
means he saw me take the horse
underwater and then watched it drown
oh how awful
anyway with that out of the way
finally that was a bit of a detour from
what i was expecting i can continue with
this
and we're basically going to be
replicating a lot of what was done on
this first layer onto here however
it doesn't seem
quite right yet i'm wondering if it
needs a little bit of a base layer here
so maybe we need like a white concrete
layer
before it just sets off in the air i'm
thinking that's probably a good idea but
it wouldn't hurt too much to make at
least the first bit here out of glass we
can always make it taller if we want
getting the shape on this one is going
to be extremely extremely difficult and
it's going to take a lot of time but oh
boy does it look pretty decent at the
moment it is not doing too badly after
giving it a lot of thought and that
prank that he's done i'm in no position
to retaliate at all now those of you
that know me from my other series
i actually am a little bit of a
prankster myself but i usually rely on
more resources than i have now i still
feel like i'm getting started i have no
mob farm i have no way of getting myself
tnt there's no shop for it
i'm not ready
but i don't think i can just let it
slide it's completely okay for someone
to go ahead and prank me they're
completely within their right and i
don't want to see anybody getting angry
at anybody but i just want you to be
aware
that
you know that you don't get away with it
you don't get to prank me and get away
with it so i've made this little room
under here we're going to transform this
little area into a secret bunker of some
kind and this is where
the list is going to be every time we
have to come down here and add someone
to the list i'm going to make this a
little bit spookier so ren you are
officially
on the list okay you are officially on
the list i'm going to have to develop
this a little bit later on but this is
going to be my secret room
just so i remember actually i should
remind myself why ren for the giant tree
and my base is not a pot hopefully that
will remind me what it is because it
might be that in a few months time i
come and have a look at the list and see
who needs pranking
and i won't remember why and that's no
good so he's officially on the list so
nobody tell him that he's on the list
nobody let him know
but one day
we'll get him back and we'll remind him
why but for now
that'll be our little secret okay now
i've made quite a decent amount of
progress
just in placing blocks and stuff it's
actually time to start placing in where
we think the towers are going to be and
it's going to be a very difficult thing
to place you see where the cyan blocks
are well i can't do that if i don't know
where the towers are going to be in the
long run i'd end up doing work that i
didn't have to do
now there's a little bit of an issue
that this is
well it's not exactly a third but this
is as close to a third as i'm
comfortable making at an angle
so this is what i'm gonna go for the
only problem is if i make a tower at
this angle it might look really really
strange it also might not and it also
could look really cool so i'm going to
plan out where this is going to be but
the difference is i'm going to make it
entirely out of this
white concrete powder and then i'm going
to pour water on it later on but that's
going to be something that i'm working
on in the background maybe next episode
i feel like i've done an awful lot of
progress to the base and it's really
starting to not look like a blender
everybody it's not a potted plant it's
not a coffee cup and it's definitely not
a blender although it look actually now
that i look at it it does look like a
blender especially with this cross thing
in the middle this straight up looks
like okay maybe i'll concede that one
also something i've been working on is
down here this is where the coral reef
is going to be now i've been slowly
placing some cobblestone here i was
trialing it anyway where i'm going to
place the cobblestone rather
here and there higgledy piggly
everywhere
and that's where the sand is then going
to go on
and then hopefully from the outside
you'll be able to see in you can see
that i made a layer down here before i
realized that the coral reef won't be
visible at all so this is another
project that i'm going to have to burn
in the background slowly adding in all
of this coral so this is very much an
artificial reef that's going to go in
here but it's going to add a huge amount
of color and light i hope
even though you have to look through the
glass which can be a bit dulling to the
the mine look you mean if you can see
the base around the outside it is very
dull i have a feeling this is where i'm
going to regret selling all of that
cobblestone come to think of it i'm sure
i've got more than enough to be getting
on with but this is going to require
quite a lot of resources
so anyway you get the idea we're going
to be creating an artificial reef here
we're actually going to be covering up a
lot of the previous work that we did
here by making this coral reef so anyway
this is just a small section that i've
covered with sand and eventually this is
going to be something really really
decorative and then from the outside
we'll be able to look down well once the
pickles are added and stuff we're able
to look down and see a bunch of color in
there and hey wait is that no that's not
paul
there's another fish in here how on
earth
did you get in there and what have you
done with paul
okay well paul's been missing for a
while now as we know from earlier
he the only way that this fish could
have got in there basically down here
there's little schools of fish i wonder
if there's any other about that of
course there's none there when i need to
show you but fish spawn here they hit
this
they get sent up and then they flop
around here now normally they end up
just flopping around here until they die
but this one
is flopped all the way over here and got
in the tank
but if i just leave him there he's going
to despawn you clever boy we're going to
we're going to take you
we're going to take you and we're going
to name you i don't want you to replace
paul
and i'm going to call you
codswallop i i like that that's a funny
word
and here we have codswallop wait
it
where'd he go
no
no no no no no no
no no no no
no no no no no no no why does everything
i love
oh
oh codswallop
i saved you
oh my goodness
never do that again right we're gonna
place you down here now
and now i've made a mess in my base oh
this is
this is a disaster
he spawned on the top
wait where is he
no codswallop
you are a nightmare fish i tell you
okay
i saved it right
you are officially the fish that lived
okay oh my goodness everything seems to
just perish before me okay codswallop
you stay there
and
hopefully you're no replacement of paul
but you chose this life not me paul
didn't choose the life of the aquarium
at least you did speaking of which we
actually need to go and put up some
missing signs because
i don't know how it would be possible he
must have fallen out and died but maybe
someone actually took him
maybe someone took paul
where did i get golden apple from so we
need to go and make a few missing signs
so i put up a missing person's sign
saying have you seen this old man if
found please contact immediately his
family miss him and hopefully they
understand who i'm talking about exactly
because this armor stand went missing
it's so sad to see this walking cane
just standing there by himself or
sitting there with no one to hold it
this this is so upsetting have you seen
this puffer fish and i've put paul in
there hopefully they know who paul
belongs to maybe not if found please
return to green's aquarium so just gonna
put up a few of these to make sure that
people see them uh preferably in places
where people are walking around quite a
lot
so maybe one over here and everyone goes
into the fireworks shop so this is a
great place to put it
okay there we go there's loads of
missing people signs up now we got have
you seen this puffer fish and we've got
have you seen this old man
i've had really bad luck this episode
i'm not gonna lie really bad luck my old
man's gone missing
my puffer fish has gone missing we've
made a new friend in cod's wallet but i
almost lost him as well
we made some pretty decent progress on
the base but we also lost a skeleton
horse we got pranked but we ended up
with loads of resources we've put ren on
our list wink wink
but i'd say all in all things are going
pretty well apart from losing the things
that i love the most
oh good
he's still here
[Music]
okay well i think that's it for today's
episode thank you very much for watching
everybody
and i will see you in the next one
goodbye
[Music]
you